Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
We're bringing you an advanced lesson today.
今天我们带来了一节高级课程。
That's right.
没错。
An advanced lesson where we talk about investing in emerging markets.
一节关于投资新兴市场的高级课程。
Right.
对。
So it's kind of a business topic.
所以这算是一个商业话题。
It's kind of a world topic as well.
也算是一个世界性话题。
Yes.
是的。
And it's pretty difficult.
而且相当难。
Yeah.
嗯。
It is really hard.
确实很难。
Right.
对。
So if you're listening and you don't understand everything, please don't get discouraged.
所以如果你在听，但没完全听懂，请不要气馁。
Don't worry about it because we're here to learn.
别担心，因为我们是来学习的。
Yes.
是的。
And we're here to help you.
我们是来帮助你的。
Right.
对。
So let's get started with this.
那我们开始吧。
I'm really excited about this lesson.
我对这节课真的很兴奋。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
Well, Marco, maybe you can tell us a little bit.
那么，Marco，也许你可以跟我们说说。
What is an emerging market?
什么是新兴市场？
An emerging market is a market that is starting to develop.
新兴市场是一个刚开始发展的市场。
Okay.
好的。
And it's growing rapidly.
而且它增长迅速。
So you can maybe give some examples of emerging market.
所以你可以举一些新兴市场的例子。
Well, for example, China is an emerging market.
嗯，例如，中国就是一个新兴市场。
Yeah.
嗯。
In the last years, it's been growing rapidly.
在过去几年里，它一直在快速增长。
More and more people are moving to the middle class and have money to spend.
越来越多的人进入中产阶级，有了可支配收入。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So China is like a really great example of an emerging market.
所以中国是一个很好的新兴市场例子。
All right.
好的。
Well, with that, let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
那么，接下来我们第一次听对话。
Dad, I'd like to borrow some money.
爸爸，我想借点钱。
Sure, Johnny.
当然，约翰尼。
How much do you need?
你需要多少钱？
Five bucks?
五块钱？
Come on, Dad.
别这样，爸爸。
I need $30,000.
我需要三万美元。
I want to get into the market.
我想进入市场。
You know, I'm tired of hearing all this news about the economic downturn, the inevitable
你知道吗，我已经听腻了那些关于经济衰退、不可避免的
recession, people stuffing their money in their mattresses.
萧条，以及人们把钱塞在床垫下的新闻。
I look at this as an opportunity.
我把这看作是一个机会。
This is a chance for me to get a jumpstart on building my nest egg.
这是我开始积累养老金的好机会。
I don't know about that.
我可不太确定。
With all the uncertainty in the markets right now, it would be a very unwise decision to
现在市场充满不确定性，投资是
invest.
非常不明智的决定。
I don't know if you're aware, son, but there has been a lot of turmoil in the markets recently.
儿子，我不知道你是否意识到，最近市场动荡很大。
There have already been half a million layoffs in the last few months, and we have no idea
过去几个月已经有五十万人失业，我们完全不知道
how the proposed stimulus package will impact upon the economy.
拟议的经济刺激计划会对经济产生什么影响。
There's just too much instability.
太不稳定了。
I just wouldn't feel comfortable investing in this climate.
在这种环境下投资，我会觉得很不踏实。
But look at it this way.
但你可以这样看。
Every challenge is an opportunity.
每个挑战都是机遇。
And anyway, I'm not talking about investing in the domestic market.
而且，我说的不是投资国内市场。
There are emerging markets that promise great returns.
有些新兴市场能带来丰厚回报。
Look at China, for example.
比如中国。
They have 1.4 billion people, half a billion of whom have recently entered the middle class.
他们有十四亿人口，其中五亿人最近进入了中产阶级。
Here alone, the aggregate demand for consumer goods represents an amazing wealth-generating
仅就这里而言，消费品的总需求就代表着
opportunity.
一个巨大的财富创造机会。
Oh, come on, son, you're looking at this too naively.
哦，得了吧，儿子，你把这事想得太天真了。
The Chinese market has exhibited a great deal of instability, and their currency has been
中国市场表现出很大的不稳定性，而且他们的货币
devalued by almost a whole percentage point.
几乎贬值了一个百分点。
Fine, then.
那好吧。
If that's the way you feel, so be it.
如果你这么想，那就这样吧。
But you're losing out on a great opportunity here.
但你正在错过一个绝佳的机会。
I'm going to hit up mom for the cash.
我去找妈妈要钱。
Well, it sounds like the dad has missed out on a really big investment opportunity, hey?
嗯，听起来爸爸错过了一个很大的投资机会，是吧？
Yeah, and his son is pretty smart.
是啊，他儿子挺聪明的。
Pretty smart little boy.
挺聪明的小家伙。
Okay, so we have some great words that we want to look at here.
好了，我们有一些很棒的词要学习。
Why don't we start with the first one, turmoil.
我们先从第一个开始，turmoil。
Turmoil.
Turmoil。
动荡。
Turmoil.
So we have some great examples of how turmoil is used in different sentences.
所以我们有一些很好的例子，展示了“动荡”在不同句子中的用法。
So let's listen.
那我们来听听。
Example one, with a civil war, a famine, and inflation, the country has been in turmoil
例子一：由于内战、饥荒和通货膨胀，这个国家已经处于动荡之中
for ten years.
十年了。
Example two, there's been a lot of turmoil in my life recently.
例子二：最近我的生活经历了很多动荡。
I've moved to a new city.
我搬到了一个新城市。
I've changed my job.
我换了工作。
I broke up with my girlfriend.
我和女朋友分手了。
Example three, the devaluation of the dollar caused a great deal of turmoil in the markets.
例子三：美元贬值导致市场出现巨大动荡。
So turmoil is a state of...
所以动荡是一种状态……
Of uncertainty, of change, of difficult times.
一种不确定、变化、困难时期的状态。
A little bit of chaos.
有点混乱。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
对，对，对。
So for example, when there's a lot of turmoil in the market, that means stock prices are
所以例如，当市场出现很多动荡时，意味着股票价格
changing drastically from day to day.
每天都在剧烈变化。
Right, or the economy is in turmoil.
没错，或者经济处于动荡之中。
There's a lot of problems going on.
有很多问题在发生。
Yeah, uncertainty.
是的，不确定性。
Uncertainty.
不确定性。
Okay, good word.
好的，好词。
All right, and we also saw something really interesting in the dialogue about a proposed
好的，我们在对话中还看到了一些非常有趣的内容，关于一项提议的
stimulus package.
刺激计划。
A proposed stimulus package.
一项提议的刺激计划。
So a proposed stimulus package is something that's going on now.
所以一项提议的刺激计划是现在正在发生的事情。
Yes, let's break this phrase down.
是的，我们来分解这个短语。
So we've got stimulus package.
我们有“刺激计划”。
A stimulus package, something to stimulate the economy, right?
刺激计划，用来刺激经济的东西，对吧？
Right, so money from the government to get the economy moving.
对，就是政府投入资金让经济运转起来。
To get it moving, stimulus package.
让它运转起来，刺激计划。
Proposed.
提议的。
It means that it hasn't been approved yet.
意思是它还没有被批准。
Right, it's suggested.
对，是建议性的。
It's suggested, it's an idea.
是建议性的，是一个想法。
So the proposed stimulus package for the US economy, for example, is $150 billion.
所以例如，美国经济的提议刺激计划是1500亿美元。
Right, that's $150 billion of American taxpayers' money that the government wants to pay.
对，那是1500亿美元的美国纳税人的钱，政府想要
Put into the economy to keep it moving.
投入经济中以保持其运转。
To keep it moving, right.
保持其运转，没错。
So if it works or not, that's still a debate, but it's a proposed stimulus package.
所以它是否有效，仍然有争议，但这是一项提议的刺激计划。
Let's move to our third phrase, aggregate demand.
让我们转到第三个短语：总需求。
Aggregate demand.
总需求。
So demand is pretty clear, but this word aggregate, what's that about?
需求这个词很清楚，但“总”是什么意思呢？
Aggregate is like a combined, added.
“总”就是合并、加总的意思。
Yeah.
对。
Right?
对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
Aggregate demand.
总需求。
So like China, where cities like in Shanghai or cities like Beijing, where more and more
就像中国，像上海或北京这样的城市，越来越多
people are accumulating wealth, the aggregate demand is increasing.
的人积累财富，总需求在增加。
Right, right.
对，对。
The combined demand for consumer goods is growing.
对消费品的总需求在增长。
Right.
对。
More people have more money, so they're spending more.
更多的人有更多的钱，所以他们花得更多。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
You know, Marco, there's a ton of excellent language in this dialogue, isn't there?
你知道吗，Marco，这段对话里有很多精彩的语言，对吧？
Yeah, a lot of good stuff here.
是的，这里有很多好东西。
Yeah.
嗯。
So let's listen to the dialogue one more time, but before we do, we have three words for
那我们再听一遍对话，但在听之前，我们想让你注意三个词。
you that we want you to listen for.
对。
Yeah.
注意这些词。
Pay attention to these words.
Nest egg.
储备金。
Inevitable.
不可避免的。
And hit up.
还有“找某人要”。
Hit up.
找某人要。
So from the context of the dialogue, try and see if you can figure out what they mean,
所以根据对话的上下文，试着看看你是否能猜出它们的意思，
but after listening to it, we'll come back and explain it anyways.
但听完之后，我们还是会回来解释的。
Dad, I'd like to borrow some money.
爸爸，我想借点钱。
Sure, Johnny.
当然，Johnny。
How much do you need?
你需要多少？
Five bucks?
五块钱？
Come on, Dad.
拜托，爸爸。
I need $30,000.
我需要三万美元。
I want to get into the market.
我想进入市场。
You know, I'm tired of hearing all this news about the economic downturn, the inevitable
你知道，我厌倦了听到所有这些关于经济衰退、不可避免的
recession, people stuffing their money in their mattresses.
经济衰退，人们把钱都塞在床垫底下。
I look at this as an opportunity.
我把这看作是一个机会。
This is a chance for me to get a jumpstart on building my nest egg.
这是我提前开始攒钱的好机会。
I don't know about that.
我可不敢苟同。
With all the uncertainty in the markets right now, it would be a very unwise decision to
鉴于目前市场的不确定性，现在投资是非常不明智的。
invest.
投资。
I don't know if you're aware, son, but there has been a lot of turmoil in the markets recently.
孩子，我不知道你是否意识到，最近市场动荡很大。
There have already been half a million layoffs in the last few months, and we have no idea
过去几个月已经有50万人失业，我们也不知道
how the proposed stimulus package will impact upon the economy.
拟议的经济刺激方案会对经济产生什么影响。
There's just too much instability.
太不稳定了。
I just wouldn't feel comfortable investing in this climate.
在这种环境下投资，我会觉得很不踏实。
But look at it this way.
但你可以这样看。
Every challenge is an opportunity.
每个挑战都是机遇。
But anyway, I'm not talking about investing in the domestic market.
不过，我说的不是投资国内市场。
There are emerging markets that promise great returns.
有些新兴市场回报率很高。
Look at China, for example.
比如中国。
They have 1.4 billion people, half a billion of whom have recently entered the middle class.
他们有14亿人口，其中5亿人最近进入了中产阶级。
Here alone, the aggregate demand for consumer goods represents an amazing wealth-generating
仅就这一点而言，消费品的总需求就代表着巨大的财富创造
opportunity.
机会。
Oh, come on, son.
哦，得了吧，孩子。
You're looking at this too naively.
你把问题想得太简单了。
The Chinese market has exhibited a great deal of instability, and their currency has been
中国市场表现出很大的不稳定性，而且他们的货币已经
devalued by almost a whole percentage point.
贬值了将近一个百分点。
Fine, then.
那好吧。
If that's the way you feel, so be it, but you're losing out on a great opportunity here.
如果你这么想，那就算了，但你正在错失一个绝佳的机会。
I'm going to hit up mom for the cash.
我去找老妈要钱。
So the kid wants to invest because he wants to set up his nest egg.
所以这孩子想投资，因为他想攒钱。
That's right.
没错。
So basically, he wants to get a bunch of cash together so that he can buy a house or get
基本上，他想攒一大笔钱，用来买房或者
married or whatever.
结婚什么的。
It's that money you need to start your life, right?
就是开始生活需要的那笔钱，对吧？
To start your life, your nest egg.
开始生活，你的储备金。
It's kind of a weird way of referring to this money, right?
这样称呼这笔钱有点奇怪，对吧？
I guess it is kind of funny.
我想是有点好笑。
And also, the little boy talked about an inevitable recession.
还有，那个小男孩提到了不可避免的经济衰退。
Yes, inevitable.
是的，不可避免。
Inevitable.
不可避免。
Inevitable basically means unavoidable.
不可避免基本上就是无法避免的意思。
Right.
对。
So this guy thinks that the recession is unavoidable.
所以这个人认为经济衰退是不可避免的。
It's going to happen.
这一定会发生。
Yes, inevitable.
是的，不可避免。
You know, this word inevitable, if you apply the root words, you can get a noun, an adjective,
你知道，这个词“inevitable”，如果你应用词根，可以得到名词、形容词，
or an adverb, right?
或者副词，对吧？
Right.
对。
So here are some examples where you can see this word in action.
这里有一些例子，你可以看到这个词的实际用法。
Example one.
例子一。
Jason knew he was going to get laid off, but he was trying to delay the inevitable.
杰森知道自己要被解雇了，但他试图推迟这不可避免的事。
Example two.
例子二。
As a new manager, it's inevitable that you're going to make mistakes.
作为新经理，你犯错误是不可避免的。
Example three.
例子三。
Inevitably, we all die at the end of our lives.
不可避免地，我们最终都会死去。
So as you can see, the noun and adjective form are the same.
所以你看，名词和形容词形式是一样的。
Yes, inevitable.
是的，inevitable。
Inevitable.
Inevitable。
When we use it as an adverb though, we add the L-Y to it.
但当我们把它用作副词时，要加上 L-Y。
Inevitably.
Inevitably。
Yes.
是的。
So yeah, as you can see, we could use it in many different ways depending on what we want
所以你看，我们可以根据想表达的意思，以多种方式使用它。
to say.
Right.
对。
Well, inevitably, we have to move on to our third word.
嗯，不可避免地，我们得继续讲第三个词了。
Hit up.
Hit up。
So he says he's going to hit up mom for the cash.
他说他要向妈妈要钱。
Ask his mom.
问他妈妈要。
Yeah, hit up.
对，hit up。
Yeah, this is kind of a slangy term, isn't it?
嗯，这有点俚语化，是吧？
Yeah, it's more informal, a lot more slangy.
是的，更非正式，更俚语化。
You wouldn't really use it with your boss, would you?
你不会真的对老板用这个词，对吧？
No, you're not going to go up to your boss and say, hey, I need to hit you up for some
不，你不会走到老板面前说，嘿，我需要向你讨点钱。
cash.
No.
不。
So Marco, I think this word is only applying to money, right?
所以 Marco，我觉得这个词只适用于钱，对吧？
Well, you wouldn't go up to your boss and say, oh, I need to hit you up for some vacation
嗯，你不会走到老板面前说，哦，我需要向你讨点假期。
time.
No, it's typically used like for money.
不，它通常用于钱。
In this context.
在这个语境下。
Yeah.
是的。
Hit him up.
找他试试。
We've got some examples of the phrase hit up.
我们有一些关于“hit up”这个短语的例子。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm going to hit up the boss for a raise.
我打算找老板要求加薪。
Example two.
例子二。
Are you trying to hit me up for money?
你是想找我借钱吗？
Example three.
例子三。
I don't have any cash.
我没有现金。
Have you tried hitting up Sophie?
你试过找索菲帮忙吗？
She's rich.
她很有钱。
Okay, so this is our first advanced lesson.
好了，这是我们的第一堂高级课。
I hope you enjoyed it.
希望你喜欢。
It is a lot more challenging, I think.
我觉得这更具挑战性。
Yes.
是的。
Especially because it's set in a business context, so it makes it... so we have a lot
特别是因为场景设定在商务环境中，所以有很多
of specific words and a lot of technical vocabulary.
特定的词汇和很多专业术语。
That's right.
没错。
Marco, you're exactly right.
马可，你说得完全正确。
And I think that our users are going to have a lot of questions about the language in this
而且我认为我们的用户会对这节课中的语言有很多疑问。
lesson.
这节课。
So I'd like to invite you guys to come onto our website at EnglishPod.com.
所以我想邀请你们访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Basically where you can leave all your questions and comments and we'll be there to answer
基本上，你可以在那里留下所有的问题和评论，我们会去回答它们。
them.
回答它们。
But until then, it's goodbye.
但在那之前，再见。
Goodbye.
再见。